Yeah, so it started with keep reading and that was, these were all created in 2017, but
came out of my notes of like things that Mary and said that I need to remember.
And which I'm sure everybody has in their notebooks across the country, across the world.
Keep reading was the first one, and I think it came out of simultaneously with the creation of the lit review podcast, which was a podcast that page May of a status daughters and I started as a sort of a response to so much rapid response work that had happened already in our cities in 2015, 2016, 2017.
And then wanting to figure out what are the containers for political education like to continue. And so we created the lit review podcast as what we call spark notes for the movement.
And it was a way for us to have conversations with our with our comrades with our with our other organizers community organizers about books that have changed their political theories of change or books that have inspired them.
Or books that even just like open them up to the world that they're in now.
And and it all just all of it went back to Mary. I'm just being like keep reading just keep reading keep reading keep reading.
And so that was the first one I started to make. And then I was like, you know, I feel like people would really find solace and value in having more of Maryam's words on these postcards.
Or on these very handheld like something you can like pass to someone something you can gift to someone versus just like a poster. And so I talked to Maryam and I was like, what if I did this like poster, I post card series and we sold them and fundraise for something that you want to defund race for.
And so of course she was like, yes, say less. She was like, let's do it. And I was like, okay, here's some ideas for what quote I want to use. So she was down may tomorrow bring us more justice and some piece that one is something that she tweets like every single night when she's done tweeting for the day.
And then that we have work to do is something that she also says a lot when it comes to whenever there's these moments of
Con like conflict or critiques or you know like outside critiques or internal critiques or
Tensions that like don't necessarily need to be tensions. She's just like, come on, we have work to do. We need to move forward and of course hope is a discipline is one that became a favorite and then turned into the cover of her first book.
So this is the cover of Maryam Cabas book. We do this till we free us abolitionist organizing and transforming justice.
This piece was originally created in 2017 and had the words and had her words hope is a discipline at the top.
So the image is up for interpretation. Some people think it's a sun. It is my interpretation is it is a moon over a moon, you know, sunsetting. I mean, not sunsetting a moon over rising over water.
And so you have the the moon's reflection on the water sort of coming out towards the forefront and then you have what are the waves are just these different abstract lines choppy lines across the water.
And the moon also has some some texture and movement in it as well, but it is super bright. I really wanted it to have just like this immense glow around this moon as it rose over the water.
And yeah, just as a as almost like a guide as a as a as a light towards of hope, right and that like clockwork right as discipline is that the moon will always rise and set and rise and set and that you always have an opportunity to change course.
And then you have to have a chance to step up to be bolder in your actions to take a break to you know we do this work until we free us like we're always going to do this work in whatever iteration.
And you can take at that moment, you just have to remember like clockwork that like it must always be present that hope must be present that that possibility and that experimentation.
Embracing has to always be present so yeah it's a little bit about that piece.
It's also it's also no surprise that people want to talk with you all too because there's this quote by Mary and Cabo also that she says write yourself into history.
Not because you're vain. Well, because you're important your work is important and you're building off the work of your ancestors and someone will be building off of yours.
So that that's why people want to talk to you that's why we're all talking about this work because we have to we have to be our own archivers our own documenters.
We have to tell our stories are also someone else is going to tell our story for us so thanks for inviting us to be able to tell our stories.